Hi everyone! These are the bamboos next to our site.
#是房東叫我們砍掉的
The landlord asked us to clear them.
#他說這個竹子長得太小啦
He said that the bamboos are too small.
#叫我們把它砍下來餵竹鼠
So he asked us to chop them down for the bamboo rats.
#那麼高
So high.
#不好爬哦
It's hard to climb.
#別擋路
Don't block the way!
#搞得我一身都是毛
It makes my covered with hair.
#啊 別擋路
Ah! Don't block the way!
#太多草
There's too much grass.
#你看 就那麼一丟丟
Look! Just a tiny little bit of bamboos,
#還說很多
and he said there were a lot.
#這根怎麼倒下去啦
Why is this one falling down?
#倒下去我也把它砍掉這個
I don't care. I'll chop it,
#倒下去的這個
falling or not.
#拿來餵竹鼠剛好
It's simply perfect for the bamboo rats.
#可以
Alright!
#你看 這根小的
Look! This is small.
#這根小的也把它砍掉它去
This small one also needs to be chopped.
#留大的
I only leave the large ones.
#小的就把它砍 砍掉
The small ones need to be chopped, chopped away.
#這也砍掉它 太小這個
And this one too. It's too small.
#沒用的
Useless.
#這種竹子
This kind of bamboos,
#要把它砍掉
can't be kept here.
#不砍掉
They won't grow,
#它也長不大
anyway.
#浪費
They're wasting,
#浪費土地資源
wasting the land resources.
#你看
Look!
#這個也把它砍掉 太小啦
I'll chop this one too. It's too small.
#看一下上面還有沒有 小的
Let me see if there're still any small ones, up there.
#這裡還有小的
Here's another small one.
#你看 砍了10分鐘都不到
Look! In less than 10 minutes,
#我就砍了那麼多 那麼多竹子給我 (註︰給自己....)
I've already chopped so many, so many bamboos for myself.
#很好砍的
It's not hard at all.
#竹子又小
They're small.
#這根也很小 這個
This one is small too, this one.
#把它摞下去
Take it down.
#看著手來 會刺手
Watch your hands. It's spiky.
#等一下我們用車拉上 上面去 餵竹鼠啦
We'll carry them up there, up there with a car, for the bamboo rats.
#你看 給它們餵一下竹子
Look! I feed them with the bamboo.
#竹子好不好吃啊
Does the bamboo tastes good?
#你看它吃竹子吃得好爽啊
Look! It enjoys the bamboo so much.
#你幹嘛 我又沒 我又沒搶你的竹子
Hey, come on! I'm not, I'm not taking away your bamboo.
#這個是公的
This is male.
#現在都瘦啦
It's getting skinny.
#它有兩個老婆哦
It has two wives.
#兩個都比 兩個老婆都比它大
Both are, both wives are bigger than it is.
#沒辦法
That's the case.
#現在公的不夠用
We don't have enough males.
#湊合著用吧
So they need to share.
#誒 好像是這個懷孕了 這個
Eh? This one seems to be pregnant, this one.
#摸摸
I can feel it.
#嗯
Um
#一個
One
#兩個
Two
#3個 就3個好像
Three. It seems just three.
#3個小崽
Three babies.
#看一下你
Let me have a look!
#這個沒懷孕
This one is not pregnant.
#你看 它一直站起來
Look! It's standing all the time.
#是不是想吃我的手 是不是
Do you want to eat my finger? Do you?
來啊 來啊來啊來啊
Come on! Come on come on come on!
#肯定想吃我的手
I'm sure that it wants.
#哎
Ay!
#掐你脖子 把你掐起來
Grab you neck! Grab you!
#公的 這個
It's male.
#雙手張開
Arms opened
#你是不是想投降 是不是
You surrender, don't you?
#還是你說別吃我
Or you're saying, "Don't eat me!"
#不是你
I won't eat you.
#我吃你幹嘛
Why should I?
#是不是
Why?
#放回去
Put you back.
#好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#我要一個人慢慢餵
The feeding takes quite a while,
#餵這個要一點時間
as I'm doing it alone, slowly.